<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2022-05-13T10:20:38+12:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Diary of a PhD student in Aotearoa</title><subtitle>Hi! I&apos;m a prospective PhD student in Aotearoa, New Zealand.</subtitle><author><name>Lucy de Jong</name><email>lucy.c.dejong@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">The end of my second week</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/13/second_week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The end of my second week" /><published>2022-05-13T00:00:00+12:00</published><updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00+12:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/13/second_week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/13/second_week/">&lt;p&gt;Welkom! It’s the end of my second week and for some unknown reason I’m pretty tired :sleeping:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my first week with mostly admin things, like scrounging for electronics and various desk-related things with the help of my supervisor, meeting a lot of people in the office, and getting my ID picture taken (still haven’t got the card though, I have to sign in at the hospital where I’m based every day without it).&lt;br /&gt;
In amongst all that, I tried to start planning projects and reading, but I found myself reading with no aim and going around in circles, not able to focus on anything. In the end my supervisor suggested I work on learning about and writing cell culture protocols (like from &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/978-1-62703-128-8&quot;&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:fn-cell_culture_book&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:fn-cell_culture_book&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) because that is one of the first things I would need to do anyway.&lt;br /&gt;
I think it gave me some direction in my reading, and now I think I have a better idea of what I need to be reading overall. So for now I’m building my own cell culture protocol.&lt;br /&gt;
While I’ve written protocols before, I have never needed to keep track of the materials needed and how much they cost before, so this part is new to me. Working out how to record and track everything is the kind of thing I enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it’s been a month since my last post, one of my aims is to write these more frequently! I do have plans for more informative ones, but I haven’t learnt much yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog_sign_off.png&quot; alt=&quot;blog_sign_off.png&quot; height=&quot;36px&quot; width=&quot;36px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;things-im-reading&quot;&gt;Things I’m reading:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immune &lt;em&gt;by Philipp Dettmer&lt;/em&gt; (Creator of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/inanutshell&quot;&gt;Kurzgesagt&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ministry for the Future &lt;em&gt;by Kim Stanley Robinson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:fn-cell_culture_book&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;McMurchy, A. N. &amp;amp; Levings, M. K. Basic Cell Culture Protocols (eds. Helgason, C. D. &amp;amp; Miller, C. L.) (Humana Press, 2013). doi:10.1007/978-1-62703-128-8 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:fn-cell_culture_book&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Lucy de Jong</name><email>lucy.c.dejong@gmail.com</email></author><category term="study" /><summary type="html">Welkom! It’s the end of my second week and for some unknown reason I’m pretty tired :sleeping:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This blog is finally working</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/21/blog_is_working/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This blog is finally working" /><published>2022-04-21T00:00:00+12:00</published><updated>2022-04-21T00:00:00+12:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/21/blog_is_working</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/21/blog_is_working/">&lt;p&gt;Kia Ora!&lt;br /&gt;
Well this blog is finally up and running :relieved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow me from this beginning, expect some changes to this format as I navigate/learn/tinker with GitHub pages, Jekyll, website development, social media … well everything I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some updates from the last post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got a university scholarship which is a big relief!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I finished up at work on Tuesday&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My project plans have gone out the window and re-entered in a more general and hopefully more manageable form (I will do a post about my studies once I figure out more of them and what I should/should not publish here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two weeks break before I officially start my studies, and I plan to use it tinkering with this blog, catching up on &lt;a href=&quot;#reading&quot;&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt;, doing some admin work for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/predatorfreechurtonpark/&quot;&gt;Predator Free Churton Park&lt;/a&gt; and getting through a chunk of my To Do list. How much will actually get done? Probably not as much as I hope!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog_sign_off.png&quot; alt=&quot;blog_sign_off.png&quot; height=&quot;36px&quot; width=&quot;36px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;things-im-reading&quot;&gt;Things I’m reading:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immune &lt;em&gt;by Philipp Dettmer&lt;/em&gt; (Creator of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/inanutshell&quot;&gt;Kurzgesagt&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ministry for the Future &lt;em&gt;by Kim Stanley Robinson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rule of Wolves &lt;em&gt;by Leigh Bardugo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Lucy de Jong</name><email>lucy.c.dejong@gmail.com</email></author><category term="intro" /><category term="life" /><category term="career" /><summary type="html">Kia Ora! Well this blog is finally up and running :relieved:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello world!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/04/hello_world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello world!" /><published>2022-01-04T00:00:00+13:00</published><updated>2022-01-04T00:00:00+13:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/04/hello_world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/04/hello_world/">&lt;p&gt;Good morning!&lt;br /&gt;
My very first blog post is all about my thoughts as I begin to plan out and get ideas for my 3-year PhD project in Wellington, New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been in the research and development department for a cancer treatment research company since I finished my Honours degree in 2016. As our department began moving in new directions I decided to take a look at what I wanted out of my career (disease and treatment research), my lifestyle (world travel with my husband) my current life situation (coupled with the world’s situation - eek!) and landed on the decision to spend the next three years doing a PhD in my home city of Wellington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intent of this blog series is to follow my life through this period of time. At this point I don’t know exactly what I want to include, but I do want to record some of the technical things that I learn, as well as thoughts on my career and research decisions. I also don’t know how often I’ll be updating, I’ll try to make it every 2 weeks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have applied for scholarships but it’s not a great time of year to be applying for them and I will have to try again soon. I am very grateful that I can continue working on a contract basis until I have funding sorted. My current boss has been super supportive, and has been giving me tips and advice on going through a doctoral program and planning out my research, which has been so helpful - I plan to put it to use in the next few weeks as I begin planning my PhD in ernest. I currently have a great overall hypothesis but only two suitable aims - I need to flesh them out and decide on a third. Hopefully a well-planned proposal will help with scholarship applications, but my doctoral supervisor reckons the decisions around here are more down to how many papers I’ve published, which apparently is not enough at this point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are numerous reasons for wanting my career to be focused in industry, they will probably come out during the course of this blog series, but the experience of applying for funding at the moment is definitely one of them! I’m very grateful that I won’t have to do too much of it during my studies. I’m very thankful my supervisor is supportive of this choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post seems to be a litany of thankfulness. It is a good reminder that even if I can’t start immediately, I have much to be thankful for already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- L&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lucy de Jong</name><email>lucy.c.dejong@gmail.com</email></author><category term="intro" /><category term="life" /><category term="career" /><summary type="html">Good morning! My very first blog post is all about my thoughts as I begin to plan out and get ideas for my 3-year PhD project in Wellington, New Zealand.</summary></entry></feed>